greatbritishchefs.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy - Great British Chefs

Great British Chefs Ltd is a media owner with the following platforms www.greatbritishchefs.com and www.greatitialianchefs.com. We are a digital food publisher for those in search of recipe inspiration, technical expertise and the latest chef and restaurant news and reviews. This Privacy Policy explains how we use information we collect from you when you use our site. We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review. Any updates will be posted on this web page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 5 April 2018. If you have privacy questions which are not answered by this Privacy Policy or any other queries about how we use your information, please contact us at info@greatbritishchefs.com.

 **Contents:**

What information do we collect about you?

How will we use the information about you?

Information sharing

Access to your information

Other websites

Site Useage

Data Protection Notice

Changes to our privacy policy

Our details

 **1 What information do we collect about you?**

1.1 Information provided by you

We collect information about you (such as your name, address and e-mail address) when you register with us, sign up for emails, e-mail us, or contact us via social media sites using the links on our website. We also collect information whenever you choose to provide it in order to use any interactive features on our website such as completing customer surveys, providing feedback and participating in competitions.

1.2 Records of website use

Our website server automatically records information that your browser sends whenever you visit a page on our website, such as your IP address; details of the web browser and operating system that you are using; the date and time of your request; the specific page requested and how you arrived at that page (eg, the search term used to find the page or link clicked to access it). This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

1.3 Cookies

We may store information about your use of our site and preferences by using cookies which are stored on your computer’s hard drive. Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies. You may refuse to accept cookies or receive notification when you receive cookies by adjusting your privacy settings in your browser. However, if you refuse cookies in a few cases you may be unable to access certain parts of our site or to use all of its functionality. [You can read more about how we use cookies on our cookie page.](https://www.greatbritishchefs.com/cookie-policy)

 **2 How will we use the information about you?**

2.1 Information collected about you

We collect information about you to manage your account and, if you agree, to email you about updates on our website that might be of interest to you. We use your information collected from the website to personalise your repeat visits to our website. Great British Chefs will not share your information for marketing purposes with companies outside Great British Chefs without your prior explicit consent.

2.2 Interactivity

Allowing you to participate in interactive features of our website, when you chose to do so; and you can opt out from receiving marketing information from us at any time by sending an e-mail to info@greatbritishchefs.com, or visiting the email preference centre to manage which emails you receive from Great British Chefs.

2.3 Marketing

We would like to send you information about updates, new recipes and features, and / or competitions that might be of interest to you. If you have consented to receive marketing email updates, you may opt out at any time.

We may add you to different newsletters with your consent based on your browsing history. These newsletters include, but are not limited to the Great British Chefs Weekly Features / Recipes Newsletter, Great British Chefs Competitions Newsletter and Great Italian Chefs Newsletter.

 **3 Information sharing**

We only share your information with third parties in the following circumstances:

3.1 to members of our group of companies (who will adhere to our Privacy Policy when using your information); or

3.2 with your consent; or

3.3 with marketing partners with whom we have obtained your consent to share the information at the time we collected it; or

3.4 we may provide our advertisers or marketing consultants with aggregate information about our users, although we will not provide them with information about individuals. We may also provide aggregated and statistical information to third parties involved in maintaining or developing our website; or

3.5 in the event of a sale or proposed sale of the company Great British Chefs Limited or its business; or

3.6 if we require to do so in order to comply a legal or regulatory obligation; to enforce our terms of use, or to protect the rights of Great British Chefs Limited or users of the site. This includes exchanging information with other organisations to help prevent the risk of fraud or credit risk.

 **4 Access to your information**

You have a right to access, modify and delete the personal information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email us at info@greatbritishchefs.com or write to us at the address given below. We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. In addition to the facilities available on our website which allow us to amend and update details relating to your account, you may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.

Great British Chefs

Unit 4 Pride Court

80-82 White Lion Street

London

N1 9PF

 **5 Other websites**

Our website contains links to other websites. This Privacy Policy only applies to this website, so when you access other websites via our links you should read their own privacy policies.

 **6 Site Usage**

Images uploaded by individuals using the Great British Chefs website or any of its channels must not contain, promote, have links to sexually explicit materials, hate material, promotion of violence, discrimination based on race, sex, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation, age, or family status, or any other materials deemed unsuitable or harmful by Great British Chefs.

Images must not promote illegal activities or violate the intellectual property rights of others.

 **7 Data Protection Notice**

7.1 The purpose of this statement is to set out how we use personal information we may obtain about you. By registering as a user of our services and by using the Great British Chefs website generally you agree to this use.

7.2 When you register and use this site you will be asked to provide certain information such as your contact details. We will store this data securely. We will use this data to fulfill our agreement with you.

7.3 We may use information you provide or is obtained by us:

a.To register you with our website and to administer our website services;

b.For assessment and analysis (e.g. market, customer and product analysis) to enable us to review, develop and improve the services which we offer and to enable us to provide you and other customers with relevant information through our marketing programme. We may use your information to make decisions about you using computerised technology, for example, automatically selecting products or services, which we think will interest you from the information we have.

c.To provide you with our newsletter if you have opted-in to receive it. We will always provide you with the option of un-subscribing within each newsletter sent or you can unsubscribe here. For the prevention and detection of fraud.

d.To administer any prize draws or competitions you may enter.

7.4 We may give information about you to the following, who may use it for the same purposes as set out above:

a.To our employees and agents to administer any accounts, products and services provided to you by us now or in the future.

We may also disclose your information:

b.To anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you.

c.If we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so.

7.5 In order that we can monitor and improve the website, we may gather certain information about you when you use it, including details of your domain name and IP address, operating system, browser version and the web site you visited prior to our site.

7.6 Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our web site. Cookies also allow us to make our web site more user friendly by, for example, allowing us to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it every time you visit our website. We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies, and you should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. This will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it.

7.7 We may supplement the information you provide to us with information we receive from third parties in order to deliver a more personalised user experience o the site.

7.8 We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal details. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose on-line. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence or willful default.

7.9 You have the right to see personal data (as defined in the Data Protection Act) we keep about you. If you are concerned that any of the information we hold on you is incorrect please contact us.

7.10 Please note that any products and services are supplied subject to our standard terms and conditions. If you have any comments or queries in connection with our privacy policy, please contact us.

 **8 Changes to our Privacy Notice**

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 5 April 2018.

 **9 Our details**

www.greatbritishchefs.com is a website owned and operated by Great British Chefs Limited.

Great British Chefs Limited 37 Aberdeen Road, London, N52UG. Registered in England Company number: 07470770

Please address any questions, comments and requests regarding our Privacy Policy to info@greatbritishchefs.com.
